free tone blockchain for everyone unique
governance system
smart contracts in different programming
languages unique nfc smart card
community driven protocol
fast and cheap transactions
scalability charging
[Music]
so
let's invite on this stage mark phillman
mark feldman ambassador of return
[Music]
ladies and gentlemen welcome to the
future
one year ago we saw a creation
of a universe the explosion that took
place
what about two and a half hours ago a
year ago
is just continuing to expand i would
like to thank
everybody that participated everybody
that contributed to this event
everybody that can continue to
contribute to the growth
into the future of free tone i also
would like to
thank the team that helped this
wonderful event happened and i would
like to open
an unofficial part
[Music]
little by little uh
we have a short video from sub
governments anybody here from sub
governments
anybody from sg all right so we have
sg all over the world and they presented
their special congratulation video so
let's watch hello friton on the behalf
of fikisub governors i would like to
congratulate
everyone on this important date the
first anniversary
our international wiki team is happy to
be a part of it
we wish friton a fast development
friendly community and lots of good
and pleasant occasions to get together
happy birthday for tom
[Music]
hello friton happy birthday from korea
um
it was such an honor to witness the
beginning of this greatest blockchain
on earth uh what you have accomplished
so far is
amazing but i know greater things are
going to happen this year
congratulations i'm so proud of you hi
everybody
i'm joanne speaking on behalf of the smm
subgov and we would like to give the
entire freeton community a huge
virtual hug and a big congrats
and happy one-year anniversary we're
looking forward to being part of a
bigger brighter
revolution that is free time
congrats
hi everyone happy first anniversary
freetown community
my name is john kaniri from nairobi
africa thank you hello community
i'm eugenia mccarron i'm a part of
tonga's team
happy anniversary a great future i wish
may the town be with you dear friends
nikita ishikov here on behalf of the web
designers of governance i would like to
congratulate freetom
on its very first birthday i want to
wish every member of the community
the most fruitful the most powerful the
most successful and the most productive
next year as only possible see you soon
happy birthday friton community
happy birthday to us
we grow fast together we are strong
happy one year celebration from all
esports up governance please and join us
[Music]
everyone is delighted with this event
tell us why you chose this particular
platform
hype city a city of bloggers so far
few people know about hype city but soon
not only free ton
but the entire crypto community will
learn about this platform we will do an
affiliate program with free time
we will generate a lot of content for
free time and this is just the beginning
this event is the starting point i think
we will meet very often
in my opinion the most significant event
for free ton
is the launch of the project itself
after all
it couldn't have taken place but
independent companies got together with
the community and launched this product
that is the project as a whole
i believe that this is the most
significant event for free time
that is its birth in essence
i think freeton's best achievement is
that we move
we are really moving towards
decentralization and we are really
moving towards the fact that in the near
future
the community will manage this project
from this point of view
freeton is the only project in the world
that has attempted to achieve
full decentralization
the main achievement along with the
technical ones
is of course the community this is
primarily
technology the network becomes more
secure
the network becomes more powerful
because more transactions can be
processed
etc at the moment the network is already
ready
for production-ready solutions
sub-management
sub-governments for example b-fair or
nft
are working to present to the world a
solution based on 3-ton
and only free time
[Music]
oh
hello everyone alexandra philitov is
with us now
alexander i'm shocked by how cool you
celebrated the year
more precisely you are still celebrating
we are still here
share your feelings and emotions how do
you like this holiday
very cool it seems to me that you got
into the atmosphere
the audience very well and i hope that
this is just the beginning
and in a year there will be more of us
we will be even stronger
so great five out of five
there are a lot of people who are not
yet in your community
but really want to join
tell us how to do it how to become a
part of the three-ton community
very simple forum.3.org
there are a ton of contests the simplest
thing is to participate
in relevant contests get ton
and become a member of the community and
develop further
this is the most obvious first step free
ton community
we are proud that we are growing that we
are getting stronger every day
and i call on all those who are not yet
in our community to join us
this is a big movement and i think a
great future is behind this
[Music]
you