hello
hi
hello everyone
hello
uh okay so let's wait one minute
after that we will start
okay
so welcome everyone to our 64th weekly
defy galleries call so we have the
presentation of flex beta uh today so
later so without further ado please
take the screen
sure i will
second
okay so well a lot of you
as we see now
join the the closed group for the
testing
of the closed beta
um
and so i don't know if
you know this
some of you have been already been able
to test as i saw
and so i will quickly
like just summarize what
what is it again
[Music]
now
before
that i will just tell that of course
currently this is not the latest version
because this is the latest public
version of course we have a
we have a
more advanced version which we're
testing internally yet but we will roll
out discussions into this closed beta as
they are
progressing
so um
so a lot of feedback that we already
that you are giving now we already got
and it will be uh refactoring but uh
again
nevertheless please please
suggest anything or report anything that
you see
so
just again few words about
about how it works
so
the website that you're using now it
won't be the website it won't be the web
interface it will it will be electron
standalone applications for for all the
platforms
separately and the reason for that is
is that we want
this experience that you can currently
like if i press here yeah it shows this
i don't know if you see my mouse but
i choose this
5.5
and uh and i
and i want to execute this order
all i have to do is this
right that's all so i just clicked on
this by 30 phillips nothing else and so
we don't want the confirmation for
every step
of your trading because
this is how
uh normal trading should look like
here's my order has been executed that's
it
now it's all changed
this is this is the the taker order and
i just bought it for five and a five you
can see this is my trade it just
happened now 1603.
so and that's experience we really want
for the user because we want to go after
finance with that ftx finance whatever
so
in order to do that we need to manage
keys
and um management of the keys and flex
is a is a very complicated
thing
but which allows very
non-complicated user experience
hopefully yeah but for managing these
keys
we don't want to leave it in the browser
so
therefore the decision has been taken to
make it a standalone application like
you have today in interactive brokers
for example or some other like clients
that you used to happen as a normal
trader
this is this allows us to have um the
built-in
experience of multi-trader kind of team
uh policy based trading as an
institutional trader would demand
and that's already done it's already
implemented and if you go to flex right
now when you start the account
you will see this qr code which will
send you to
auth debug and serve and auto debug and
serve
is actually
what you if you
if you're not an individual trader but
if you want to create a team
of traders then you will just pass this
link to your superior to your manager
and your manager will operate the old
debut from his account from the central
account which can be mortgage account
for example and uh and then he will give
you or she will give you
the allowance like she will send you
deposit you into your account this
like so i have this deposit so this was
deposited
and if you go and you do it yourself if
you send if you just use your qr code
with your own surf account and you will
go through this procedure now today this
debot is very complicated not
complicated but it's it involves several
steps
these steps
are there to deploy all the accounts
that are necessary accounts and index
accounts
because we need to
know
uh how many of these wallets has been
deployed to in order to manage that it
can support like 100 traders and each of
the traders will have you know many
may have many
tip three because right now it's only
flx
you have the market on the influence but
obviously you can have many of the you
will have many of the currencies here
and in order to manage all that
you need to deploy a lot of a lot of
stuff a lot of indexes and and so on and
so forth so
therefore it's it's currently it will be
refactored this debate so it will be
easier
but but right now you just go through
the steps
there so once you are once you are done
and yeah we know that there is a lot of
like unnecessary complexities where they
ask you twice to what um amount you want
to deposit and not very intuitive we're
working on making this much simpler this
devote
but if you go through that if you click
all the buttons you will see this
that will give you like the amount of
the t3 this all of that is three tip
three
so you have tokens right now like evers
and about some flex already
and you have also the the
the native evers on each of these tip
three these are just to pay the fees
right so you have to remember that's
that was i was making the mistake by
deploying by depositing hundred thousand
and because of this debt when i used it
first time i also didn't know what it
all means so yeah that that happens
but anyway you can destroy the account
you can you can take this money back so
it's not you know it's not stuck there
forever but nevertheless
so these are these are the keys now
flex will not
use
a native token so it all wrapped but we
are not going to tell that it's wrapped
the user doesn't need to know that for
from our perspective so all tokens you
will see here will be just
if you go to
binance today all the tokens that you
have there or the currencies that you
have that are all wrapped
because they're all just numbers in the
database but nobody tell you that and
use and we don't want to complicate user
live to
go and to
go wrap the token unwrap the tokens see
this is wrap talk and not trap talking
we just operate on this is the token
this is your balance and when you go
withdraw this which currently is not
working yet but when you there will be a
button withdraw here when you withdraw
the tokens the wrap the wrapper will
just do automatically
will deposit you unwrap tokens back into
your wallet
and it will all be like users won't
don't need to know that that they have
rap tokens so so it's it will never be
here so
we will see bta btc here like bitcoin
you will see ethereum here and all of
the tokens
without any knowledge of the europe not
trapped not not interesting
okay what else so
um
here you you will see all your like
balances including the balances that are
currently in orders
um which means inorders means here
basically my maker orders so remember
that flex supports in taker maker now
taker maker is one of the
you know
obviously inherited features of the
order book exchange the difference
between taker maker for for
whoever doesn't know that is that
maker
is somebody who provides liquidity
so for example i have two orders where i
am making so i i i'm you know 970 and
600 rotating 5.3 this this
this is my order was yeah this is my
order you see this is on open order i
provided this liquidity whoever will
trade against me here so taker will will
want to come and execute that
uh i will see it here as a here as a
maker so that's execution against my
open order as a maker and i get the fees
kickback so this fee is actually i'm i'm
making that fee
the taker pays
the fee and part of the fees goes to
maker whoever provided the liquidity so
this is one of the things where we
encourage someone to provide liquidity
because on every trade you get you get
obviously the kickback in infants so now
you can see all this all this kickbacks
and here in your trade history
trades are here these are all the trades
well
last several trades of the
yeah you know of the whole thing
here is an order book and here is the
trading view and depth uh
so you can see the order book depth here
and you can go and see
like
oh depth of the whole because you you
don't see all the order book here
because you only see like you know
whatever is fitting here so in order to
see all the order book here we can go
here and you can see it's quite deep
someone wants to buy them on 0.1
anyway
uh so yeah and and then a normal trade
in view like in any other exchange with
all the
nice features
that you can have here
um and so on so that's that's pretty
standard now see here you see
like the
you know statistics um
for the for this particular market token
felix against them
now
what works right now it's actually
these orders currently are not limit
orders so this is
just going to change i mean the limit
order is not yet implemented will not be
in the first version it will be in the
second version quite soon but we we
would just want to
first deal with spot order so everything
you see here is spot so if i click here
6 and 230
great 230 tokens on 6 i can buy some of
them let's say i want to buy like 30
immediate or cancel this works this flag
means that the order will be executed or
not so if it's not executed i will get
the funds back
um
so let's let's put this order so i i
will i'm going to buy here and i will
limit order will not perform this
operation like that limit order if i put
six
uh you know price six and 30 it will
actually collect the 30 from from here
from 5.6 here it was executed yeah the
5.6 because it's better price okay so
limit order will actually go search for
better price the best execution and in
your limits of course the limits you
will need to uh
okay but i i hope you know what limit
orders means
okay but
of course we will support limit orders
because it's actually limit order board
distributed limit order book so yeah
limit orders will be executed but not on
the first step so right now you you will
just need to click and you know spot
do the manual work of limit orders
but because it's very fast
actually as you can see
you can manage that quite quite easily
this
other than that because limit order will
be executed on the bots so in a way it's
the same like the bots will see whatever
you see
and it will just execute that
automatically the logic that you can do
manually okay so so nothing fancy and we
will do limit orders quite simply
but um
[Music]
but right now it's uh the more
interesting types of orders are good
good until executed
and stuff like that which which will be
quite tricky to implement but we will do
that as well so right now okay
immediately cancel works post order
works that's a make your order so if i
put if i put
cell
num six and thirds the same you see here
is still
uh there so if i put that here right now
in pause that it will be adding here
nobody will will you know it will not be
executed so i will just add liquidity
here with this order
on that by the way
we have a bug right now in um
in subscriptions because we moved from
pooling to subscriptions
some subscriptions don't work um in i
think in order book so you may not see
this updated but
uh it will be fixed today
if it's not fixed already
all right so you have this post if you
don't put post or
image of the cancel if you execute an
order that will be it if you don't have
the full order
fulfillment it will execute the taker
order on the part that it has
as it is possible to fulfill and then
the rest will be left as a maker order
so it's like partial maker partial taker
quite simple
quite
standard stuff actually
so um
well i think uh that's more or less that
actually
questions
good thank you so much media for
presentation
uh no has questions yes no please
will it be possible to cancel orders for
example yeah absolutely yep so of course
no
we don't want any cancel no of course
the cancel order uh is already done in
the newest version of the but we're not
yet not going to make it
you know
days time
okay
any other questions guys please
uh okay maybe a question for myself
yeah well don't forget to raise your
hand
sorry
will there be any guides for developers
to to develop on top of flex and it's
already it's already is it's already
there there is a there is a
documentation already for flex and flex
apis flex and yeah yeah but there is no
there is no market maker sort of
documentation how to develop market but
there is a base contract for market
maker but uh
like uh the examples which are
likely the euro market makers are pretty
complex so uh either some like starter
guide for for implementing simple
strategies
well um you can you have two ways to
implement strategies
uh one way is through
uh debots
like or or external apis is what the way
you want it doesn't matter
which which will be executed by your
server
that's one
uh simple kind of solution to that if
you want to decentralize market maker
then you must execute it the way we
provide the sample for imo so you can
take our ammo use it or or change it
but in general
um
you will need to can amms are complex
you will need to understand how it works
in order to like write something or they
take our amm by the way this is not the
last version the last version will be
published soon but um nevertheless they
you will have to take our contracts and
use yeah notifications because you will
need your market maker to understand the
last order so yeah you will need to kind
of
uh unfortunately learn all that
yeah for sure and the the second
question is
i'm thinking about the
uh
the platform there are a lot of
platforms
on top of centralized exchange which is
like uh like a bill you have building
blocks like averages and the different
analytics stuff and you can like
combine them to implement strategies and
script and uh how how
how do one approach to build such a
product so what what you're doing by api
yeah you take the api that we provide
this is a special endpoint for flex uh
so special cloud endpoint for flex
you go which will be chargeable right
now it's free but it will be it will be
for me of course
so um so you go there it implements
very specific queries
on top of flex order book which are
optimized to performance
to performing those queries
like for example
it can return you
the
array of contracts assaulted
by certain
key oh wow that's great yeah yeah so so
it it makes an optimization for
performance of the queries for the for
the order book so you go there
and you study this api
and then you you just
you know implement whatever you want
on top of it so you can take historic
data you can query with historic data
with that and so on and so forth yeah
cool and uh continuing the the the topic
of uh salted contracts how do
the
the dub cluster
double so imagine i i hold some dub
server and i want to extend it with with
some uh extended like indexes for for
assaulted contracts how is there any
like documentation or approach which
no
this is something that is um you will
have to develop yourself if you want not
to use cloud because this is the cloud
uh cloud did a lot of efforts and
supporting this and uh they probably
want to charge for that
um so if you're okay so you can use our
you can
yeah there is no place to open source
that
obviously you can do that yourself you
can take the server and optimize the
queries and so on for what you need to
work with flex because all the obviously
everything is on chain so you can you
can quite easily
kind of study that and do that
but because guys already did that they
want some money monetization of the of
this thing and flex by the way is going
to pay clout as well
you know for sure for sure and yeah and
the last one i promise the last one for
me is uh uh so imagine i have uh like no
not imagine i have uh light nodes like
light light client process light line
which is like separate implementation
and how do you think uh does it uh
is it is it hard to to uh
introduce some support of like indexing
here
so well i i'm i'm not very i'm not very
i understand i just need to say
i know address it for example
yeah well i i'm
i think uh it will be quite hard but uh
i'm not very very familiar with the
you know
what what uh
limits kind of roxas introduced
to this um
to the to the implementation of the
of the last node so i don't know what
what information they do have there and
so on
all right thank you
you can text me questions yes i i will
check with with guys that's not really
important i'm just i'm just wondering
just for us maybe no
that's actually a good question so that
we could also understand
ways people are using uh
indexer sdk so
uh
well well yeah you need to update you
need to update it by the way to you yeah
we're already already in progress
because like people are complaining
yeah
okay
no please
i don't know if this is the right place
to ask but can you explain how does how
will the market
orders will work because that sounds
complex
the market yes
well the market order is the is the
current best price order
opened right you want it's it's just a
swap basically so the easy swap will be
with the that we will determine the
best price of open order so the best
open order price right now is you know
5.6
then it will be just executing this
market and if it's not fulfilled
if you have like if you want to buy 400
it will be just do 5.6 and then find 5.7
so in a way it's like reverse limit
order
um
that's it
it's not a very complex option
my market order is quite not complex
so somehow concurrently so if somebody
uh wants to eat
the the
glass
yes
just just just just just take the just
put the last large orchard order on the
market larger than like take all this if
you want to eat all that
just just you know
make a arithmetic operation
yeah yeah and if somebody sends the same
message
will be will we be concurrently eat
this
uh whoever comes first as you know
okay so so is it atomic for the one who
came first
it is the one who came first it is it is
not
it is a classic
uh order protocol it is not
fancy stuff like new york stock exchange
is doing
but
they have a problem
they are trying to solve because
of this
of the
you know of the limitations of the
algae limit they're not limitations but
deficiencies or differences over
efficiencies okay of the algorithmic
trading
i don't know how to put towards the foot
on this but anyway so this is
because they have this so they need to
introduce more like
a little bit fair
stuff into the market so they that's why
they are
uh
thinking about like imagine a high
volume but we are we are yeah but we are
i think because
uh it is quite uh
you know in in the case of blockchain
particularly never scale implementation
flex
um it is quite hard to get unfair
advantage
simply because you are
i don't know you have more resources
right because it will still be you will
still need to
have a lot of validators on the network
control you know yourself in order to
make it possible for you to somehow
squeeze your
your
orders uh you know and it will be
very hard to do anyway because once
because your
your
external message does not go to the
to the order book
as you have right now in any other decks
like solana where your external message
is actually what what goes to the order
book in our case of course it goes first
to your wallet contract which resides in
one place and then it goes the internal
message to the and because of the
different timings of this block
executions
you you don't you can't predict this
like you can't predict
what order your internal message will
come to the order book even if you
control validators it will be hard to do
yeah but you can you can see
no you cannot see other orders i mean
but you can but when you will see other
orders it will be already too late
ah understood because of time
yes
so i don't currently see
i thought about that a lot actually i
don't see a like a real strategy that
you can perform
here with the and take advantage of the
just
of that
right
the front running it's it's really hard
to implement front training here
especially
sorry especially when the when the
project when the queue of the external
messages would be would work
oh the ramp yes the ramp it's almost
impossible yeah
the drama is almost impossible okay
i also wonder so uh on traditional
exchanges
on success i mean so uh when you uh want
to
get the better performance so you try to
put your market makers into the same
collocation
the exchange is using
but uh in terms of uh of flags so
which which way could
help one
to
perform implement the hft so is it
possible here even
it is possible but fair meaning that you
can have
you can analyze the order book you can
put algorithms you can make algorithms
sell imm in a way in is hft
because i am reading the orders on chain
getting notifications unchained from
every order executed and then can can
perform some strategies you can
obviously do that off chain it will just
make you
one more
message
i would say
it's almost the same
and
i don't think you can i don't i don't as
i said i don't see a strategy
where one can just clearly have an
advantage like
taking
a validator and putting this in the
collocation or
i don't know
the other validates it just won't help
you in this respect
because because it's so mitigated by the
architecture of the blockchain so in
that respect i think it's much fairer
much more fair
um
way of trading than any
sex today
okay
but the market maker and but yeah and
the market maker obviously has an
advantage of of size always you know so
it's a fair advantage it's a fair
advantage right if you put make your
orders you will make some money on maker
orders of course you can make some money
on the
not only on the
like the fees
structures but of course
you know we will introduce obviously the
liquidity
farming like you did in the in the
cube
and and so so to encourage more
liquidity the market maker liquidity and
you know there are there will be
obviously many ways to do to do money as
a market makers
good
and by the way so the fee structure so
uh
for now it is controlled by uh by your
team but do you have
some mechanisms to introduce a
decentralized way of how these fees will
be controlled obviously so they set uh
for each payer separately
meaning their rebates and the fees so
yeah the fees are controlled by will be
controlled by dao
so there will be obviously
felix talking will will control the dao
and the dao will decide on all this and
all this is is not just the fees
structure but also
the
the liquidity because the fees are
taking the native tokens and they are
all these fees which are which these
fees which are take your pace they all
collected into the smart contracts of
this and this reserve smart contracts
and this reserve smart contracts
they uh always accumulate
the fees they will never pay them out
and the structure is fair thou structure
so you the only way to get this
fees out
is to
exchange burn some some ethics tokens
against them
um so the the flx tokens they have
limited supply so
like um
and
in this in this reserves because they
will always grow
like
except for when someone is is is
you know burning their felix tokens
against them but it's it's it will be
real rare really rare because
it's better to send to just celebrate
than just to burn
and um and this
will give the possibility to use these
reserves as for example additional
liquidity or loans or or you know
supporting the marginal trading and so
on and so forth and all that decisions
will be taken right now as well
okay so and um when do you think
you will
be able to launch the dow so
what what is the plan
um
it we are going to launch the dow quite
soon because the the flex token is
already
like on sale
to some
investors
and uh but they're not physically yet
available
but there will be ideal on flex itself
so
maybe the dao won't have like the full
functionality
but
the flex token will come first and then
the functionality which connects to this
tokens will come a little later just
because simply to write that take time
but yeah
i mean we we want to go it's like as
soon as possible that's the answer we're
not planning like to do it
in in a year or something
good good
okay so uh guys any more questions
submitted please
okay seems there are no no more
questions so thank you very much media
for this beautiful presentation so and
uh
yeah so we i also have seen that there
are quite a number of people coming to
this uh beta testing group
so hopefully they will provide some
valuable comment to you and help you to
improve the product
yes thank you yes so i call to everyone
so please please
as usual the user's feedback is
something that developers appreciate the
most and this is something that really
helps uh
to understand better your needs
uh okay so uh actually
uh this is
all for today uh so there are two
contests running currently uh the one
for ssi stage four and the other one for
the never stage two so for some reason
they as usual didn't deploy in the
interface but i already asked interface
team to do this
so uh and uh if i remember it well it
will end
in six weeks from start so this is
something like end of april
uh so if you feel capable please go and
participate in this contest so the more
the mother's merrier
and
yeah that's pretty it for today so if
you have any other topics to discuss
just raise your hands and please
and if not so
i will count three
two
one
okay guys thank you for coming and thank
you as usual so see you next time uh
hopefully next week at the same time so
now it is 3 p.m ct so
thank you who noted this
so see you next week then
ciao