hi
all
i think we are live now uh if you can
please turn on your cameras
to say
hello to each other hey anton i see you
yeah i think let's give them two more
minutes to come
to join us
here on our
ama session and
then we will start
with the show
[Music]
hi andrew
do you hear us
i bet now
she had no headphones
maybe he can hear us even without his
headphones
hello
maybe
hi hi guys
girls
do you have johnny with us
i think no
no and if we can't hear
so waiting waiting
for a moment
for other petitions
maybe
could you turn on your cameras
and what about you now oh yeah now we
hear you
so i'm waiting for john or maybe we can
start from a small intro from andrew
yeah but so there are only 10
participants
what about
youtube
oh we have
several several
questions on youtube
okay
yeah let's church
then once you're gonna
just preparing some
other stuffs
okay
so um
hi hi everyone my name is andre
i'm
a member of surf's team so
um unfortunately
kenny who is a
product owner on like
father of swords i'll say
unfortunately he cannot
present himself
because he is sick
but nonetheless let's uh so we try to do
the best and
present you our 12 tokens
that we launched yesterday during the
um
community call
um first the fall
so everyone knows uh in who is
ever skill about the sword so it's
the main and famous
we call it browser
and wallet for every
forevers
and
so
the
the main idea
today's calls is to answer on your
questions regarding the tokens so if
you'd like to speak regarding the
surf products and so on uh we can make
another call or a special amy station
about the products of surf but currently
we would like to
to give you more details about tokens
so the main page i would like to share
with you the our
domain web page
tokens but in a second
okay
uh you see
yeah i should see it
yep
so um
eversorf
slash tokens or the main page we can
where you can find more detail more
information about tokens about the uh
our future plans and so on
and uh there are
some
stages at that moment so the first one
is sold out is our
um
for investors currently we are on the
strategic stage so where we would like
we'll be happy to
attract uh 10 million sword tokens
um our expectations about 2.5 million
dollars
uh evaluation and
the pricing of tokens uh will be changed
during the
the period
and
the allocation will be from
100 000 till 1 000 source tokens
so let's
go deeper
and
yeah
uh there are also on the website you can
find the two
[Music]
uh main documents the sort of pitch desk
and the sort of token uh
the
short information about tokens
um about the plans and details about the
swarf you can find on the short pitch
desk
i like to also show it
for you
and
so um i don't know
regarding the participant of yesterday's
call but uh the main information
was already
presented by joe
thanks
um here for
this presentation
and um so you can find the information
regarding the swarf here so first of all
uh what's
what token is the sword is
utility talking oh sort of talking is
utility talking uh
so it's not like a government talking
and so on so we
would like to give you ability to
participate
in source features
and
so if you'll scroll down
you'll see uh the
the main
on benefits of surf tokens
so it will be
loyalty program for
owners of sort of tokens it will be
cashback rewards
it will be
other fees
or
owners
it will be some additional features
and it will be extra benefits that we
would like to present you later
we
so the program
the loyalty program will be announced
later so currently
we
like book our
participants to
would like to buy tokens
and the
distribution of tokens will be later and
during this period the
all the benefits will be described
additionally
so um
what about the distribution so as i said
so currently we are strategic sales
so it's about
yeah with the total capacity the total
volume that we like
uh it will be
100 millions but currently so it's like
10 of them
and the cliff period
will be
um
one year
and the vesting will be two years
from
this moment
from yesterday
starting here from yesterday
and
what
um
exactly
wanted
to hear from us it will be
more positive or more effective if we if
we can answer on you some of your
questions
or just
give you
okay it's because uh i will i would like
to
like to
read or to show you the presentation
that already you can find on the website
so uh for me uh the communication with
you is which will be more helpful on
what do you think so and do you have any
questions or yeah
several questions
uh but most of them are in russian so
i'll try to translate
yeah and also i would like to announce
that the russian imagination will be
tomorrow
and so we can also
discuss in in russian regarding this um
this topic so but nonetheless let's
of course let's answer on the questions
yeah first of them is about
why is it
is it exactly
exchange errors on surf tokens
uh yes it is
yes why not
i mean uh the ever stock we buy
we buy self tokens
on error tokens
yeah it's uh it's it's one way
one one one way years uh you can buy uh
soft tokens uh
uh forever but if you have
the tokens
udt btc ath or other tokens we also
accept it for payments but it will be
it wouldn't be through the debate
um directly so you will need to contact
me either
in telegram or send
your
send message to us to talking at
eversource and we will negotiate we will
discuss it and find it
the best way to evaluate the price and
yeah and put all of this information to
debate where you can find later the
information regarding to your trades so
we accept all tokens we
not only ever
yes but accepting errors is the easiest
way
you can
go to the site
self ever dot surf slash token
and there is a link to the board in
which you can buy self tokens forevers
uh it's the main
i think way
the easiest way to do it but if you have
some other tokens please come to andrew
or to the team and we would
find the way to do it
and um yeah and also the fiat payments
if feel like you have
idea like priority to buy
using the fiat payments on a web
transfer or like we can also discuss it
okay thank you
then then the next answer is after cliff
uh could could we
uh
have all the sum after
cliff ends
without
wasting
process
[Music]
written on this site
i think this is a small misunderstanding
maybe because
after cliff you would
the tokens would become gradually um
releasing but
there are no percents
i think western is a number of months
during which you would gradually
receive your tokens
uh am i right enter yeah absolutely
so the the users will get
the tokens after they leave
next
question is about
killer whale tokens
would it be a cross course of kilowatt
tokens and surf tokens
yeah why not so
we hope that text
exchanges will support both tokens and
will be the pair will be created why not
yes thanks
then the next question
are you planning to create your own
exchange
or
to integrate with flex
we are not going to
so we will i
you will the
like text services will be available in
swerve but we are not going to create
own exchange because we have like we
have flex we have other maybe we'll find
other providers who can do it domain or
text
i mean the main exchange flex will be
integrated to the source app
yeah i think that flex is our strategic
partners so
a server would be a mobile terminal for
this exchange
and uh you can find it in our road map
so yeah
flex not our own version of exchange
um
then
the next question
[Music]
or why
so little tokens is left for liquidity
pool
andrew could you help this question
yeah i'll see i'll show the distribution
at first um
it's um
so because it's utility tokens and
because um
so we are not
we are not going to
um
make it to create a bubble
so
with
talking sales
and uh when we start so we have
um i associate with their we have like a
partners who
we support trading
on
exchanges
but uh for our expectation one percent
of them is
enough for uh
for trading and for supporting the
trade value
during the
first stages
we hope that market will create
the real price for it without
extra
contributions
and i missed one question
um
for what
tasks
are you planning to use surf search
token i i think
as a salary is set so you can find this
information
our pgdesk page and so it's a loyalty
program cashback rewards
special fees
extra features
and
additional benefits that will be
announced later
uh i think we can maybe
talk about an example of
using a surf token inside survey
for example
we have
currently we have a partnership with the
gift cards pro service provider
and
we can
the first i think the first case for
using surf token would be
integration with them so in surf you
would be able to
buy some gift cards
um from
for different
[Music]
shops or
internet shops
e-commerce sites
and then you would have some cashback
and surf tokens
locked for this
purpose
so
um for service providers the use would
be to
use our audience and to use our
interface to make people access
their services in a native way
so i think it would be
a win-win situation for both sides for
users and for service providers
just as an example
of usage
then
next yeah we have many many ideas how to
how to use these tokens like during for
stakings for
um
for purchases for top up the balances
and so on so uh so they will be
integrated i'll say in each products
that will be available in surf
yeah for example talking about staking
we can add additional validators to
the stake button inside surf
and
that would help them to have more tokens
in their stakes in their depots or for
users uh it can be um
increasing their
revenue their reward is taking
if
they have some surf tokens
so
i think
also it could be
a
multi-leveled
program inside the server when on
different levels you have different
possibilities it could be for example
calls insights are
available for
surf token holders and etc so there are
a lot of ideas and the first would be
gift cards and then we'll see
how it
would go
how it would be like
uh should i read the next question
[Music]
what are the
terms of
self-talking
of starting of self-talking free
how to say it
free cell
through exchanges or bots
i didn't engage
uh you can read it in
youtube
what are the
terms
ata
eta of
serve becoming available
for free selling
for free buying
i think not
[Music]
not inside our program but after
after it
wait a moment please
[Music]
if anyone can help you with translating
i would highly appreciate it
yep
okay um
the free float so um
you can it's easy to understand when the
tokens will be available for public
if we'll see the graph
let's go to
another slide
no i can i catch the gear yes
uh what is searching for
and you see the uh
the second slide
in the
tokens
or i need to switch
i think it is on this website when you
click on
tap on icon
information icon
yep so
uh so if you'll see the
the
the second the pdf file on the website
sort of token you can find the vesting
channel
uh
where you can find you can understand
when the tokens will be available on
public
and
we also have the graph
unbox shadow
where you can see that during the
the same period with the
the tokens will be available
so um the first tokens uh for private
sales will be available
in uh
uh
after the
so we
first of all
when we'll start the next stage so
the private sale
which will be available for every
community
and
strategic cells also
during the
um
how they call it uh
kill whale
podcasts and so on so you can also buy
mr tokens
but for private
trades it will be available during the
half half of year so after the six
months the first tokens will be
available for public
okay thank you
then
why
did you decide to
sell
tokens not only for errors but
for other tokens
[Music]
yeah um
why why other tokens also yeah because
we
everyone
so we need to
support our
team our efforts we need to
to pay salaries to our employees we need
to
to pay for marketing we need to pay like
for designs for other features that we
do so we have expenses
so we also use um
the sales for to support it our
operation needs
so
if we will attract only ever so we'll
we're not we would like
to keep it we are not going to sell it
and reduce price
so um
this is one of the
reason
why we also
attract other tokens or like if you have
payments
yeah i think also we can speak about
every scale instruments in the whole
and when we
started uh
thinking about uh self-talking we find
out that uh not all the instruments in
in
for fast and easy
um
exchange of different tokens uh exist so
uh
now an andrew helps with uh buying
surf uh tokens for other tokens but
if we
um
have enough instruments maybe it would
be made in a deb also in a debate way
so i think this is one of our tasks to
make
[Music]
working without tokens possible
in our ecosystem
in more easy and comfortable way
where
can i see the progress
or how many investors
have already bought
uh the second
[Music]
second option of tokens
second series of tokens
uh i think you can see it on the
side again it's every dot surf slash
token
if you scroll it a bit
down you'll see a
block about
how many investors
have already bought
and current
number is i think
16.
okay
uh wrong could you help me with
uh reading questions please it's a bit
difficult to
read and answer at the same time
yeah for sure
there is a question from i see from the
alexanovic of uh he joined
uh he joined in our zoom call and i
think that he want to ask it uh
via voice
yeah alexa go ahead
hello i just wanted to ask
i
went through
utility token purposes
liar loyality cashback reduction of fees
and
enhanced futures and nuclear benefits
i don't see
something that cannot be done using ever
coins
do you have some purposes of your token
that is not possible to
replace with errors
this is my question thank you
thank you
um
okay go ahead oh you can start entering
okay
yeah
so of course every is like a main
uh token of your scale
but uh
so you can you cannot find currently uh
like
cashback's functions
for instance uh
uh
also
we of course we can use only error for
all these features
but for us it's like a principal
decision that it should be our tokens
should be a service tokens see the
loyalty of community to serve up to
understand uh the evaluation of um our
efforts of our
um
like of our job lc
and
for
so
we would like that
uh
it's also one of the promotion when you
see the sort of token so you can
understand uh
the
will be maybe easy to calculate or your
your rewards for some
features that you used in sword because
you will get uh these tokens for
for for staking for instance for cards
and so on
it's like uh
[Music]
it's extra talking to every scale
it's it's not going to
to change the functions of error it's
impossible due to the
algorithm specific
so i hope yeah
this is
all that
currently i would like to say
yeah thank you
thank you
it is not governance
it is not government content you are not
go you are not planning to
add some governance
yes
yes yes correct absolutely so the this
is just it's um you chill it's
principles it's a pretty it's hugely
talking it's not regardless
so uh because
so you will have no rights to
um
lead to manage uh the decisions of the
source tokens so we hope that uh all
that we've done all that we are planning
to do
um
you are satisfied with this and you
support us
because so we have an incredible amazing
team and so
the sword currently with like lc with
the best interface for everscale so and
we try to keep this line to keep this
efforts
and show you the best features
in every
with your scale
i just want to add that for me
i the idea essential idea of surf as a
browser
to make
it comfortable
to communicate with the blockchain and
to build a bridge between users
not only current community but
you can say all with users all over the
world and
service providers
and
this is the value
of surf
connecting these two
worlds
and solving problems for both sides and
for me
self-talking is not only utility token
but it's only a part of this idea
idea of
putting together these two areas
of business and life
and
making it very smooth
and comfortable for both sides to
work with it to communicate to interact
to solve their problems
and in this way self-talking is a part
of the error scale it's another
structure but it has its id and its idea
of is the same as in the surf
its
idea of making this bridge
and making it comfortable to use
okay how have we answered alex
to your question
yeah
just
still it means that it's some kind of
i don't see actually real benefits
for the community having another token
if it is not governance token of course
but
as you said it will not be governance
so
just still
i don't
see any reason
for this
but a good answer thank you okay
thank you for sharing your thoughts
um
maybe let's go to this
next question
do you have any plans to promote the
messaging function of surf app
i think it's one of the
crucial
possibilities
in
for decentralized world to be able to
message
in a private secure
and safe way manner
and
one day i'm sure we would
go back to this
feature but right now our
team is rather small and
for do this to promote this feature to
make it
more interesting
we need
i don't know several more people
to be able to work on
this
feature too
so on our roadmap we
right now for this year we do not have
this feature as a as i remember
if i'm not right please
guys
[Music]
yeah and you're
curious but uh i also like to return to
the previous
couple of questions so when you when
you're talking about the short talking
uh you also invest in swarf
uh to
to develop these new features to
um to develop surf
and uh if the surface will be like more
more functions joyful fault
like i don't know like other
defined
main brands uh it's mean that the price
of the tokens will be also rised
so uh
it's not like it's the same the
messenger so if
we'll
have enough investments so we'll start
these
procedures
we prioritize this feature messenger and
so the extra people will be
um
involved in this project
thank you
now we have a
message not a question
from our term by the way you have a
great product i love your design thanks
a lot we are working hard to make it
good
and
[Music]
to enjoy using so that you can enjoy
using it
oh no no can i see smart code
smart contracts code root address api
[Music]
yeah
okay but i don't understand what's what
what's do you mean can i see smart
contracts code root address api what
contrast do you mean
i don't know maybe maybe
could you please collaborate and write
your questions
we have a
lot of different smart contracts what
do you want to see
maybe the bots
if you talk about talking it will it
will be tip free compatible tracking
yeah yeah first it would be
tips
and it does not mean it yet so yeah well
wanting we are planning to meet it in uh
i think uh end of april
because we have some principal questions
with current uh realization
from roxas and we're waiting for flex
talking so that surf can work
self-talking can work on
any decentralized platform
so now uh there is no smart contract as
i understand
am i right nikita
yeah you're right we continue to develop
the standard itself to free
so
when we will complete some
issues we
will start to implement it
so it will be tip 3 or tip 3.1
you mean
there are differences between this
standard as i know tip 3 is
a top maybe very common description
of
the series of standards and tip 3.1 is
describes very basic
fields
and functions and
it also inside
tip-free standard as i understand
but they support different methods
actually to get information about token
for example
we still needed to be
changed a bit about
previous old format of tp but now is a
wrapper with the
old all the tips
of every scale and
one of the tips to free and inside the
standard
now uh there is three point one and
there will be some other
sub
sub sub interfaces
substandards to three point two and so
on and uh
i think i can say yes for your
question because it's t 3.1 compatible
i think it would be even even another
some other format of tip three because
we needed to be
to work with flex and
flat cube all both of them
so i think that
you would be able to see the contract
root address and so on before the
meeting so end of april i think it's
there
as
broxas did
after upgrade
so
we will support this standard too
okay
i hope we answered yeah
and next question is about our roadmap
on your roadmap quarter four then
support will take
dotsof or dot error
i think
both
of them
because it's important for the network
on the whole
but for
surf tokens
holders there would be some additional
benefits i think this is answer
and i
i don't see any more questions
so
maybe
if
we have
someone in zoom who want to ask
something
uh it's your time
if no
or maybe on youtube one more question
the final one
if you have something to ask please do
otherwise i think we should
uh
stop today's
and just i would like to see that if you
have any questions uh don't hesitate to
contact us so you have several options
to do it
um
the
you can ask assistant in the surf
app
you can
chat with us in telegram we have a
special
channel for for it
uh we created the group um
we you're gonna send us email
as i said before talking at everett
itself
or you can
contact with me
kenny and directly
if you have like any questions regarding
the like specific questions
so um so we are open for you
and try to do try to answer as soon as
possible in the short run
and
thank you for your questions here
we hope that
you will be enjoyed the
surf during
this year
despite of the situation so we are
working hard and
so
it will be it will be nice features
coming soon so
we are not stopped our project so we are
going further
yep thanks you for your attention and
questions you have rather big road map
and uh talking about telegram channel
you can always write us
in our
our channel called surf ever
in one word
this is the english speaking channel
or in a better search channel where
available everywhere i think
or
even you can even
use
our old forum for it on
forumfritton.org
so thank you for your time for
being with us today oh we have one more
question
uh can you open the boat code
nikita
deport code
which is what
i think
yes
maybe not today because
we have
uh now we're working on this progress to
open source some the bots for our
previous projects for example for
boosted
staking
for
the pulley and so on and we will
continue
this problem
this process but the first will be
boosted thinking not talking
talking sale so it's on the list yeah
it's on the list yes right
oh thanks a lot i think
[Music]
sometimes i need to copy some text from
the
screen and i cannot do this
directly so i have to open
my console
select html tags and do this
using this different difficult way
could you
change
uh sure could you please
give us more details you can write me in
telegram for example
into what places exactly do phases
all places
for example whenever okay
for example
i want to and
[Music]
it's on telephone because you can double
tap on any text
in web exactly
maybe not in
apps but i check
it is in browser and sometimes i i want
to copy some information from the
browser
web yeah you can double click on any
browse the box information
and it will be
in your
copy paste
okay if you want to you can write me in
telegram and i will show you how to do
it
okay thank you i i will show you
or if you still uh would have this
problem virginia would
give go to our team and
ask us to
fix it finally
so i think the best options yeah the
best option to discuss this issue in
like better sort of uh
telegram chat and you're gonna
assist you
yep
thanks a lot axe for the question yeah
so
thank you everyone
yeah i think yeah you run away any
questions for you
no new questions
so uh one more time so uh tomorrow at
what what time and
i think it would be
uh
5 p.m cet central european time as if
i'm not mistaken
okay but we will make announcement about
it
so uh
some if you have some problems or like
more questions will be raised so ask us
tomorrow or send us yeah thanks a lot
thanks a lot to see you don't hesitate
to ask
goodbye
my