everscales remp
what is it
remp stands for reliable external
messaging protocol and it's a major
technological milestone forever scale
it makes the network faster and more
reliable let's try to give rem an
overview so we can understand how
important it is for the network
reliable message queue
in everscale messages deliver
information and instructions from one
smart contract to another or from a user
to a smart contract
messages initiate transactions which are
executed by smart contracts there are
two types of messages in everscale
internal a message from one account on
the blockchain to another that can carry
information about a transaction these
don't require a cryptographic signature
external a message sent and received
from an external source outside the
blockchain usually from the user's
device external messages need to be
signed with the user's key
in other blockchains external messages
can be a problem as there's no way to
define a strict queue order and priority
that's why blockchain users have to deal
with front running when messages they
send with trading orders for dexes are
of low priority than front runners
orders remp solves this problem and
makes everscale the only blockchain in
the world that guarantees a strict order
for message execution
how remp changes the game the main
purpose of remp is to guarantee that
messages are delivered from any network
participants in a particular order
within a sub-second time frame when a
network participant sends a message to
the network it gets accepted by the
current validators and included in the
message queue cat chain mqc with a
timestamp the validators send
confirmation of acceptance to the user
and the message is guaranteed to be
included in the block even if the block
production fails the messages will be
included in the same order they were
received in the next block if a message
doesn't end up being included in the
block all of the validators have their
stakes slashed
there's also replay protection and
anti-spam protection what's more remp
means users can get a sub second
response in dap interfaces because we
already know the message queue order
when we click thanks to this everscale
becomes not only the fastest blockchain
in terms of transactions per second but
also the most interactive
blurring the lines between regular
applications and dapps